Ernest Joseph King Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Ernest Joseph King Papers 1908-1991 1936-1952
MSS38787
King, Ernest Joseph, 1878-1956
10,000 items
39 containers
15 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Naval officer. Official and general correspondence, orders to duty, speech, article, and book file, memoranda, notes, printed material, photographs, and other papers relating primarily to King's activities as commander in chief of the United States Fleet and chief of naval operations during World War II.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Arnold, Henry Harley, 1886-1950--Correspondence.; Attlee, C. R. (Clement Richard), 1883-1967--Correspondence.; Baruch, Bernard M. (Bernard Mannes), 1870-1965--Correspondence.; Bradley, Omar Nelson, 1893-1981--Correspondence.; Chandos, Oliver Lyttelton, Viscount, 1893-1972--Correspondence.; Clark, Mark W. (Mark Wayne), 1896-1984--Correspondence.; Doolittle, James Harold, 1896-1993.; Eberstadt, Ferdinand--Correspondence.; Edison, Charles A., 1890-1969--Correspondence.; Edson, Merritt Austin, 1897-1955--Correspondence.; Edwards, Richard S. (Richard Stanislaus), 1885-1956--Correspondence.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969--Correspondence.; Freeman, Douglas Southall, 1886-1953--Correspondence.; Halsey, William F. (William Frederick), 1882-1959--Correspondence.; Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955--Correspondence.; Hungerford, Charles Frederick Algernon Portal, Viscount Portal of, 1893-1971--Correspondence.; King, Ernest Joseph, 1878-1956.; King, Ernest Joseph, 1878-1956. Fleet Admiral King; a naval record. 1952.; Knox, Frank, 1874-1944--Correspondence.; Litchfield, P. W. (Paul Weeks), 1875-1959--Correspondence.; Marshall, George C. (George Catlett), 1880-1959--Correspondence.; Nimitz, Chester W. (Chester William), 1885-1966--Correspondence.; Reynolds, Quentin James, 1902-1965--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945--Correspondence.; Sherwood, Robert E. (Robert Emmet), 1896-1955--Correspondence.; Thompson, Dorothy, 1893-1961--Correspondence.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972--Correspondence.; Whitehill, Walter Muir, 1905-1978--Correspondence.; Wright, Orville, 1871-1948--Correspondence.
Organizations
Allied and Associated Powers (1914-1920); Argentina Conference (1941); Cairo Conference (1943: Cairo, Egypt); Potsdam Conference (1945: Potsdam, Germany); Quebec Conference (1st: 1943); Teheran Conference (1943: Tehran, Iran); United States. Joint Chiefs of Staff.; United States. Navy Department. Bureau of Aeronautics.; United States. Navy--Submarine forces.; United States. Navy. U.S. Fleet.; Yalta Conference (1945: I︠A︡lta, Ukraine)
Subjects
Aeronautics, Military--United States.; Atomic bomb.; Guadalcanal, Battle of, Solomon Islands, 1942-1943.; International relations.; National security--United States.; Navy-yards and naval stations--California--San Diego.; Navy-yards and naval stations--Connecticut--New London.; Nuclear arms control.; Nuclear weapons.; Security, International.; Submarines (Ships)--Salvaging.; World politics.; World War, 1939-1945--Aerial operations, American.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Pacific Area.; World War, 1939-1945--Congresses.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.; World War, 1939-1945--Naval operations, American.; World War, 1939-1945--Peace.
Places
Tokyo (Japan)--History--Bombardment, 1942.
Titles
Atlantic Charter (1941)
Occupations
Naval officers.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Ernest Joseph King were deposited in the Library of Congress in 1970, 1971, 1991, and 1998 by the Naval Historical Foundation and converted to a gift in 1998.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Ernest Joseph King are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1887, Nov. 23 Born, Lorain, Ohio
1901 Graduated, United States Naval Academy, Annapolis, Md.
1901 1903 Duty in USS Eagle and USS Illinois, European Station
1903 1905 Duty in USS Cincinnati
1905 Married Martha Rankin Egerton
1914 Commanded USS Terry
1916 1919 Assistant to commander in chief, Atlantic Fleet
1923 1926 Commander, Submarine Base, New London, Conn.
1926 Commanded USS Wright
1927 Duty, Naval Air Station, Pensacola, Fla.
1928 1929 Assistant chief, Bureau of Aeronautics
1929 Commanding officer, Naval Air Station, Hampton Roads, Va.
1930 Commanded USS Lexington
1932 1933 Student, United States Naval War College, Newport, R.I.
1933 Promoted to rear admiral
1933 1936 Chief, Bureau of Aeronautics
1936 1937 Commander, Aircraft, Base Force (Scouting Force), San Diego, Calif.
1938 Promoted to vice admiral Commander, Aircraft, Battle Force
1941 Promoted to admiral Appointed commander in chief, United States Fleet
1942 1945 Chief, naval operations
1944 Appointed fleet admiral, United States Navy
1948 Retired, United States Navy
1952 Published with Walter Muir Whitehall Fleet Admiral King: A Naval Record. New York: W. W. Norton
1956, June 25 Died, Portsmouth, N.H.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Ernest Joseph King (1878-1956) extend chiefly from 1908 to his death in 1956, with the bulk of the material concentrated in the period 1936-1952. The collection consists of correspondence, subject files, memoranda, reports, orders, notes, and associated material organized in six series: Orders to Duty; General Correspondence; Subject File; Speech, Article, and Book File; Miscellany; and 2023 Addition.
In the early years of his career, King was a submarine officer and from 1923 to 1926 he was commander of the Submarine Base in New London, Connecticut. There are several folders of material for this tour of duty, the most important of which documents the salvaging of the S-51 sunk off Block Island in September 1925. King was in charge of the successful raising of the S-51, considered an outstanding accomplishment as it was generally thought that a submarine could not be raised from a depth of 125-130 feet of water. For this he was awarded the Distinguished Service Medal.
From submarines, King moved into aviation, qualifying as a naval pilot in 1927. In 1933 he was appointed chief of the Bureau of Aeronautics, serving in that post until 1936, when he assumed command of the Aircraft Base and Aircraft Scouting Force in San Diego. King was promoted to vice admiral in 1938 and given command of all the aircraft carriers of the fleet. Files for this period of his life are a valuable source for studying the growth and development of military aviation.
King's papers for the World War II period and beyond are particularly significant. As commander in chief of the United States Fleet and chief of Naval Operations, Admiral King attended the Atlantic Charter Meeting (1941), the Quebec Conference (1943), the Cairo and Teheran Conferences (1943), and the Yalta Conference (1945). After the war, various individuals frequently sought information from him concerning these conferences and also about particular aspects of United States military and naval operations. Wherever possible, King was ready to cooperate and supply essential information. For example, he explained to Quentin James Reynolds and Robert E. Sherwood the origins of General James Harold Doolittle's 1942 air raid on Tokyo. Marine Corps General Merritt Austin Edson was interested in learning the story behind the Guadalcanal campaign. King responded with a letter of four pages that detailed his determined efforts, over strong opposition, to strike the Japanese in the Solomon Islands immediately after the Battle of Midway (June 1942). The letter also reveals the evolution of King's philosophy of Pacific strategy, beginning with his personal experiences at the Asiatic station during the early years of the century. Other correspondence in this vein is that of Walter Muir Whitehill, coauthor of Fleet Admiral King: A Naval Record (1952); Merritt Austin Edson for Pacific Island strategy; Bernard M. Baruch, on international control of atomic weapons; Ferdinand Eberstadt, on national security organization; and Richard S. Edwards, on matters relating to the Joint Chiefs of Staff. Material in the Subject File supplements much of this correspondence.
The Speech, Article, and Book File contain manuscript drafts of Fleet Admiral King and the rough notes for the book. Also in the file drafts and final copies of King's speeches and lectures. Material from his teaching days at Annapolis and items such as his thesis written at the Naval War College (1932) on “The Influence of the National Policy on the Strategy of a War” show the development of his thought in the field of world politics.
Important correspondents include Henry Harley Arnold, C. R. Atlee, Bernard M. Baruch, Omar Nelson Bradley, Oliver Lyttleton, Viscount Chandos, Mark W. Clark, Charles A. Edison, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Douglas Southall Freeman, William Frederick Halsey, Cordell Hull, Frank Knox, P. W. Litchfield, George C. Marshall, Louis Mountbatten, Earl Mountbatten of Burma, Chester W. Nimitz, Charles Frederick Algernon Portal, Viscount Portal of Hungerford, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Dorothy Thompson, Harry S. Truman, and Orville Wright.
The 2023 Addition includes a 1991 issue of Pull Together, a newsletter of the Naval Historical Foundation and the Naval History Center, with the article “Admiral King talks about Allied Strategy, July 1943,” and a declassified copy of King's 1947 speech “Some Aspects of the High Command in World War II.”
Arrangement of the Collection
This collection is arranged in six series:
Orders to Duty, 1912-1956
General Correspondence, 1908-1957
Subject File, 1924-1957
Speech, Article, and Book File, 1908-1953
Miscellany, 1909-1966
2023 Addition, 1947, 1991
Container List
- Orders to Duty, 1912-1956 (Box 1)
  Orders to duty.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1912-1956, (9 folders) (Box 1)
- General Correspondence, 1908-1957 (Box 2-18)
  Letters received and copies of letters sent, telegrams, invitations, memoranda, and miscellaneous attachments.
  Arranged chronologically according to King's various commands and therein alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - 1908-1916 (Box 2)
  - 1917, Jellicoe, John
  - 1917-1924, (10 folders)
  - 1925-1932, (12 folders) (Box 3)
  - 1933, “A-W” miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - 1933-1936
    - “A-R” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - James, Edwin W.
    - “S-W” miscellaneous
    - Tyree, Alexander M.
  - 1936
    - Mayo, Henry T.
    - Puleston, William D.
  - 1936-1937
    - Memoranda
    - Owen, George T.
    - Wright, Orville (Box 5)
    - Yount, Barton K.
  - 1936-1938
    - “A-C” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Cook, Arthur B.
    - “D-G” miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Greenslade, John W.
    - Gutmann, Addis
    - “H” miscellaneous
    - “I-L” miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Invitations
    - Land, Emory Scott
    - “M-Z” miscellaneous, (6 folders)
  - 1936-1939, Standley, William Harrison
  - 1937
    - Cabot, Godfrey L.
    - Pownall, C. A.
  - 1937-1938 (Box 7)
    - Kalbfus, Edward C.
    - Walsh, David I.
  - 1938
    - Andrews, Adolphus
    - Arnold, Henry Harley
    - Ayres, William A.
    - Bloch, Claude C.
    - Halsey, William Frederick
    - Litchfield, P. W.
    - Memoranda
    - Stark, Harold R.
  - 1939
    - “A-H” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - “C-H” miscellaneous
    - Cook, Arthur B.
    - Halsey, William Frederick
    - Invitations
    - “J-R” miscellaneous
    - Memoranda
    - Pihl, Paul E.
    - “S-Z” miscellaneous
  - 1941, Atlantic Fleet (Box 8)
    - “A” miscellaneous
    - Andrews, Adolphus
    - “B-I” miscellaneous, (8 folders)
    - Ingram, Jonas
    - “J-K” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Knox, Frank
    - “L” miscellaneous
    - Litchfield, P. W.
    - Lovett, Robert M.
    - Memoranda miscellany
    - Morison, Elting
    - “N” miscellaneous
    - Nimitz, Chester W.
    - “O-S” miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Sinnott, Arthur J.
    - “U” miscellaneous
    - Yarnell, Harry E.
    - “W-Y” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - 1941-1945 (Box 9)
    - “A” miscellaneous
    - Adams, Charles F.
    - Adams, Phelps H.
    - Andrews, Adolphus
    - Andrews, Bert
    - Arnold, Henry Harley
    - Attlee, Clement R.
    - “Ba-Be” miscellaneous
    - Baldridge, Harry A.
    - Barbour, W. Warren
    - Barron, Carter
    - Baruch, Bernard M.
    - Beale, Marie (Mrs. Truxton Beale)
    - Beardall, John R.
    - Berryman, Clifford
    - “Bi-Br” miscellaneous
    - Biddle, Francis
    - Blake, Geoffrey
    - Blakely, Charles A.
    - Bonesteel, Charles H.
    - Bonner, Herbert C.
    - Brace, Donald C.
    - Bradley, Omar Nelson
    - Brandt, Raymond P.
    - Brennan, Walter
    - Bridges, Styles
    - Brooke, Alan F.
    - Brown, Constantine
    - “Bu” miscellaneous
    - Burton, Harold H.
    - Butterfield, Hilda
    - Byrd, Harry F.
    - Byrd, Richard
    - Byrnes, James F.
    - “Ca-Ch” miscellaneous (Box 10)
    - Carter, Boake
    - Childs, Marquis W.
    - “Cl-Cu” miscellaneous
    - Clark, Mark
    - Compton, Lewis
    - Corrigan, Frank P.
    - Cubbison, Donald C.
    - Cunningham, Andrew
    - “Da” miscellaneous
    - Daniels, Josephus
    - Davies, Joseph Edward
    - Davis, Elmer
    - “De” miscellaneous
    - Defrees, J. R.
    - Denebrink, Francis C.
    - De Vasconcelloa, Alvaro R.
    - Devers, Jacob L.
    - Dill, John
    - Dillon, Clarence
    - Do Valle, Edmundo J. Amorin
    - Donovan, William J.
    - Douglas, Lewis W.
    - Drake, L. Francis V.
    - Dreyer, Frederick C.
    - Drummond, Roscoe
    - Dutton, Eric
    - “E” miscellaneous (Box 11)
    - Edison, Charles
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D.
    - Eliot, George Fielding
    - “Fa-Fe” miscellaneous
    - Fadiman, Clifton
    - Farley, James A.
    - “Fo” miscellaneous
    - Forrestal, James
    - Freeman, Douglas Southall
    - “Ga-Go” miscellaneous
    - George, Walter F.
    - Gerhauser, William H.
    - “Gr” miscellaneous
    - Grosvenor, Gilbert
    - Gutmann, Addis
    - “Ha” miscellaneous (Box 12)
    - Harris, Winder R.
    - Harter, Dow W.
    - Harsch, Joseph C.
    - “He” miscellaneous
    - Henle, Raymond Z.
    - Hill, Lister
    - Holcomb, Thomas
    - Holman, Rufus C.
    - Hoover, J. Edgar
    - Hopkins, Harry
    - Howard, Roy Wilson
    - Hull, Cordell
    - “I” miscellaneous
    - Ickes, Harold L.
    - Ingram, Jonas H.
    - “J” miscellaneous
    - Jacobs, Randall
    - Johnson, Louis
    - Jones, Jesse
    - “Ka-Kin” miscellaneous
    - Kalbfus, Edward C.
    - Kefauver, Estes
    - King, W. L. MacKenzie
    - “Kir” miscellaneous
    - Knowland, William F.
    - Knox, Dudley W.
    - Knox, Frank
    - “La-Le” miscellaneous (Box 13)
    - La Guardia, Fiorello H.
    - Land, Emory Scott.
    - Landon, Alfred M.
    - Lawrence, David
    - Leahy, William D.
    - Lee, John C. H.
    - “Li-Ly” miscellaneous
    - Lindley, Ernest K.
    - Lippmann, Walter
    - Litchfield, P. W.
    - Little, Charles
    - Luce, Henry Robinson
    - Lyttleton, Oliver
    - “Mc” miscellaneous
    - McCormick, Robert R.
    - “Mag-My” miscellaneous
    - Magruder, Marshall
    - Maitland-Wilson, Henry
    - Marshall, George
    - Memoranda
    - Morgenthau, Henry (1891-1967)
    - Mountbatten of Burma, Louis Mountbatten, Earl
    - “N” miscellaneous (Box 14)
    - Nash, Walter
    - Nelles, Percy W.
    - Nelson, Donald M.
    - Nimitz, Chester W.
    - Noble, Percy
    - “O” miscellaneous
    - O'Mahoney, Joseph C.
    - “P” miscellaneous
    - Patton, George S.
    - Pepper, Claude
    - Plumley, Charles A.
    - Portal, Charles F. A.
    - Pound, Dudley
    - Pratt, Henry Conger
    - Pratt, William V.
    - Prince, Frederick H.
    - Pye, William S.
    - Quezon, Manuel L.
    - “Ra-Re” miscellaneous
    - Radcliffe, George L.
    - Radford, Arthur W.
    - Ranneft, J. E. Meijer
    - Reeves, Joseph Mason
    - “Rh-Ri” miscellaneous
    - Richey, Thomas Beall
    - “Ro-Ry” miscellaneous
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A.
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D.
    - “Sa-Se” miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - Sarnoff, David
    - Scrugham, James G.
    - “Sh-Sp” miscellaneous
    - Sheppard, Harry R.
    - Sherwood, Robert E.
    - Simons, Manley H.
    - Smith, Edward H.
    - Smith, Frederic H.
    - Smith, Holland M.
    - Somervell, Brehon
    - Somerville, James F.
    - Spaatz, Carl
    - Spivak, Lawrence E.
    - “St-Sz” miscellaneous
    - Stark, Harold R.
    - Stettinius, Edward R. (1900-1949)
    - Stimson, Henry L.
    - Stout, Rex
    - Stratemeyer, George E.
    - Sullivan, Mark
    - Sulzberger, Arthur Hays
    - Swing, Raymond
    - Swope, Herbert Bayard
    - Symington, Powers
    - “Ta-Ti” miscellaneous
    - Taussig, Joseph
    - Thomas, Albert
    - Thompson, Dorothy
    - “To-Tu” miscellaneous
    - Train, Charles Russell (Box 16)
    - Truman, Harry S.
    - “U” miscellaneous
    - “V” miscellaneous
    - Vandergrift, Alexander A.
    - Vandenberg, Arthur H.
    - Van Wagner, Harry G.
    - Victory, John F.
    - Vinson, Carl
    - “Wa-We” miscellaneous
    - Waesche, Russell R.
    - Walsh, Arthur
    - Walsh, David I.
    - Walsh, John H.
    - Warner, Rawleigh
    - Wedemeyer, Albert C.
    - Welles, Sumner L.
    - Wells, Briant H.
    - “Wh-Wy” miscellaneous
    - Wheeler, John N.
    - Winant, John G.
    - Winstead, Arthur
    - Woodruff, Roy O.
    - Wright, James L.
    - Wygant, Benyaurd B.
    - Wysong, Cooper Beale
    - “Y” miscellaneous
    - Yarnell, Harry E.
    - “Z” miscellaneous
  - 1946-1957 (Box 17)
    - “A” miscellaneous
    - Adams, Charles F.
    - Arnold, Henry Harley
    - “B” miscellaneous
    - Baruch, Bernard M.
    - Berendson, Carl A.
    - Blandy, William Henry P.
    - Bliss, Robert Woods
    - Burke, Arleigh
    - Byrd, Richard
    - “C” miscellaneous
    - Churchill, Winston S.
    - “D” miscellaneous
    - Daniels, Josephus
    - Drake, L. Francis V.
    - “E” miscellaneous
    - Eberstadt, Ferdinand
    - Edison, Charles
    - Edson, Merritt Austin
    - Edwards, Richard S.
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D.
    - Epstein, Julius
    - “F” miscellaneous
    - Fairbanks, Douglas (1909- )
    - Farley, James A.
    - Forrestal, James
    - Freeman, Douglas Southall
    - “H” miscellaneous
    - Hoffman, Clare E.
    - Hoover, Herbert
    - Howard, Roy Wilson
    - Hull, Cordell
    - Ingram, Jonas H.
    - “K” miscellaneous
    - Kai-shek, Chiang
    - Kinkaid, Thomas C.
    - “L” miscellaneous
    - Lausche, Frank
    - Leahy, William D.
    - Litchfield, Paul W.
    - Little, Charles
    - “M” miscellaneous (Box 18)
    - Marshall, George C.
    - Morison, Samuel Eliot
    - Mountbatten of Burma, Louis Mountbatten, Earl
    - “N” miscellaneous
    - Nimitz, Chester W.
    - “O” miscellaneous
    - Patterson, Robert P.
    - “R” miscellaneous
    - Reynolds, Quentin James
    - Rosenman, Samuel I.
    - “S” miscellaneous
    - Sherman, Forrest P.
    - Sherman, Frederick C.
    - Sherwood, Robert E.
    - Smith, H. Alexander
    - Spruance, Raymond A.
    - Stark, Harold R.
    - Strauss, Lewis
    - Sullivan, John L.
    - Symington, Powers
    - Truman, Harry S.
    - “U-V” miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Vinson, Carl
    - “W” miscellaneous
    - Walsh, John H.
    - Whitehouse, Rempfer L.
    - Wilson, Lyle C.
    - Yarnell, Harry E.
- Subject File, 1924-1957 (Box 19-26)
  Correspondence, memoranda, notes, photographs, and printed material.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Annual report to the secretary of the navy, 1944-1946, (4 folders) (Box 19)
  - Awards and decorations
    - General, 1942-1948, (2 folders)
    - Honorary degrees
      - Bowdoin College, Brunswick, Maine, 1945
      - Clarkson College, Potsdam, N.Y, 1945
      - College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Va., 1942
      - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 1945
      - Miami University, Oxford, Ohio, 1946
      - Northwestern University, Evanston, Ill., 1945
      - Oxford University, Oxford, England, 1946
      - Princeton University, Princeton, N.J., 1943
  - Biographical file, 1933-1947
  - Board of Medical Survey, report on King's condition, 1948 (Box 20)
  - Condolences and other material relating to King's death, 1956-1957, (8 folders)
  - Conferences
    - 1941, Atlantic Charter
    - 1942-1945, (3 folders)
    - 1944-1948, outlines
    - 1945, Potsdam, Germany
  - Congratulatory messages, V-E and V-J days, 1945
  - Genealogy, 1946-1948
  - General Board, 1939-1949, (3 folders) (Box 21)
  - Horne, Frederick J., 1942-1943
  - Inventions and ideas
    - “A-W,” miscellaneous, 1942-1943, (2 folders)
    - Anti-submarine, 1942-1944, (2 folders) (Box 22)
  - Investigation of the national defense program, Canol Road Project, 1943-1946
  - Joint Chiefs of Staff charter
  - Jones, John Paul, 1947
  - Memoranda for the secretary of the navy, 1942-1944, (3 folders)
  - Naming of vessels, 1942-1944
  - Naval aviation, 1933-1936
  - Naval War College (Box 23)
    - International law
    - Lectures
    - Operations problems
      - Aug.-Nov. 1932, (2 folders)
      - Nov. 1933
    - Tactical problems
      - Aug. 1932
      - Jan. 1933
    - Thesis, 1932
  - Press and press releases, 1942-1948, (3 folders)
  - Public relations, 1944
  - Reunions of class of 1901, United States Naval Academy, Annapolis, Md., 1944-1947
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., death of, 1945
  - Salvaging the submarine (Box 24)
    - USS S-51, 1925-1928, (9 folders)
    - USS S-4, 1927-1928, (9 folders) (Box 25)
  - Spare files, 1936-1938
  - Stark, Harold R., 1941-1943
  - Study of air logistic organization and procedure, 1944
  - Universal military training, 1944-1945 (Box 26)
  - War College correspondence course, 1924, (5 folders)
  - West Coast logistic organization, 1944
- Speech, Article, and Book File, 1908-1953 (Box 27-36)
  Handwritten drafts, typescripts, printed copies, and other material including related correspondence.
  Arranged by type of writing with statements and writings of others filed at the end.
  - Speaking invitations, 1942-1943 (Box 27)
  - Speeches
    - 1925-1943, (7 folders)
    - 1944
      - Jan.-Aug., (4 folders)
      - Sept.-Dec., (4 folders) (Box 28)
    - 1945-1946, (8 folders)
    - 1947-1948, undated, (6 folders) (Box 29)
  - Statements before Congress, 1943-1947, (10 folders)
  - Articles (Box 30)
    - 1908-1953, undated, (10 folders)
  - Messages
    - 1942-1943, (3 folders)
    - 1944-1949, (5 folders) (Box 31)
  - Fleet Admiral King: A Naval Record
    - Walsh, John H., 1948-1951
    - Whitehill, Walter Muir, 1946-1952, (6 folders)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1945-1952
    - Holograph and typescript drafts, undated, (17 folders) (Box 32)
    - Typescript copy (Box 33)
      - Chapters 1-13, (13 folders)
      - Chapters 14-17, (4 folders) (Box 34)
    - Handwritten and typewritten notes; flight log books
      - 1923-1950, (13 folders)
      - Undated, (6 folders) (Box 35)
  - Comments by King on drafts of an official history of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, 1945-1951, (4 folders)
  - Comments by King on histories of World War II, 1946-1950
  - Miscellaneous notes
  - Speeches and writings of others (Box 36)
    - Dickens, Gerald, 1946-1947
    - Foster, Cedric, 1944
    - Mayo, Henry T., undated, (2 folders)
    - Simons, Roger L., 1946
    - Whitehill, Walter Muir, 1946, (5 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1928-1949
- Miscellany, 1909-1966 (Box 37-39)
  Printed matter, memorabilia, photographs, newspaper clippings, and other material.
  - Printed matter (Box 37)
    - 1909-1944, (5 folders)
    - 1930-1931
    - 1945-1966, (5 folders) (Box 38)
  - Calling cards, 1944 (Box 39)
  - Certificate, 1926
  - Cross index sheets, 1944
  - Dedication of King Hall, 1956